Sohyun Lim

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+44 7435 900 850 · shlim0410@gmail.com London, United Kingdom



Enjoys learning new technologies and adapting them to products. Also quick to learn domain knowledge and, with a user-centric perspective, focus on making the user experience better and better with attention to detail.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, React, Next.js, Node.js, Express, Koa, MongoDB, SQL, ODM(Mongoose) / ORM(Prisma), Git

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Hi Street

2023 -

Web platform to create and run online stores

- Worked in a team of 6 developers and followed git workflow and agile methodology
- · Implemented database schema and built secure API routes
- Developed backend server and frontend client for store owner (order & product management)
- Tech stack: Typescript, React, NextJS, Tanstack query, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, TailwindCSS, Stripe, Turborepo, Cypress

Full Stack Developer, Bob

2023

Web service to help scheduling employees' shifts

- · Restructured Database Schema and added Authentication midddleware
- To make code reliable, converted JavaScript toTypeScript and added test with Cypress
- Tech stack: Typescript, React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Cypress

Full Stack Developer, Cafftime

2023

Web app to keep track of caffeine intake

- Built the app from the ground up: developed backend server and frontend client
- Tech stack: React, Node.js, Koa, MongoDB, Mongoose, TailwindCSS

Human Resources Manager, Banksalad (Seoul, South Korea)

Mar 2019 - Aug 2020

- Managed employee onboarding, employee welfare systems, performance assessments
- · Processed monthly payroll, incentive compensation, year-end tax adjustments
- · handling employee and stock option contracts

Web Content Team Lead, Banksalad (Seoul, South Korea)

Sep 2017 - Feb 2019

- Created over 500 high-quality articles to provide financial information to customers
- Set up SEO to improve search engine rankings and web service growth Boosted MAU by 200% by optimizing contents to appear on the first page of Google search results for over 50 major keywords

Product Support Specialist, Banksalad (Seoul, South Korea)

Jun 2015 - Aug 2017

BankSalad is a financial management app that provides personalized financial advice and offers various financial products

- Conducted user and IT service research: benchmarking services, user interviews
- Conducted research on finance products and designed a database and logic to calculate customer profit mostly collaborated with backend team

EDUCATION

Codeworks (London, United Kingdom)

2023

Software Engineering

Sogang University (Seoul, South Korea)

Mar 2010 - Feb 2015

Bachelor's Degree - Communication and media studies / Chinese Culture (Double Major)

GPA: 3.5 / 4.3